Finding Aid for the Paul Rotha papers LSC.2001
UCLA Library Special Collections
Paul Rotha papers
1914-1980
UCLA Library Special Collections
Rotha, Paul
LSC.2001
42 Linear Feet (84 boxes and 7 oversize boxes)
Paul Rotha (1907-1984) was a film critic, documentary filmmaker, and movie director. The collection consists of materials related to Rotha's documentary and feature films and Rotha's books on the cinema.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9929766903606533
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Motley Books, Limited, purchase, 1967. Paul Rotha, purchase, 1980.
Biography
Paul Rotha was born in London, England on June 3, 1907; a former painter and designer, he became a film critic and wrote a seminal work on cinema history titled, The film till now (1930); began making his own documentary films in association with John Grierson and was a leading figure in the British documentary movement of the 1930s and 1940s; directed three feature films in the 1950-60s; writings include: Documentary film (1935), Rotha on the film (1958), and The innocent eye: A biography of Robert Flaherty (1963); died on March 7, 1984.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of projects, early treatments, narration scripts, technical plans and shooting scripts for Mr. Rotha's documentary and feature films. Also includes manuscript, typescript, and proof copies of Rotha's books on the cinema along with clippings of his periodical writings and review articles. Reviews and articles on Rotha are both loose and in scrapbooks. Includes Rotha's personal diaries as well as correspondence from John Grierson, Eric Knight, and Richard Griffith, among others. There are art works from the 1920s, photographs (mostly location stills), and recording tapes from Rotha's films.
Arrangement
Collection maintains the exiting order of materials upon transfer to UCLA.
Motion picture producers and directors -- Archives.; Screenwriters -- Archives.; Film critics -- Archives.
- Film Company Projects, 1937-1939, circa 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "The golden whip" (De gouden swipe), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Public Opinion", 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "The power of peace", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Ring of fear", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Challenge of television", undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "The endless colonnade", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "The tongue-tied canary:, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Fight to survive", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Projects (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Land of promise", 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "No resting place", 1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Reviews. Film Weekly., undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Articles and reviews, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Articles and reviews, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Articles on the documentary film., undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- World Union of Domentary, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Articles from Public Opinion, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Articles and reviews., undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Articles and index, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Press clippings 'Films' (2 scrapbooks), 1926-1928 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Press clippings, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Press clippings, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Clippings on or by Rotha, 1927-1934 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook of general clippings on films, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Clippings. 4 scrapbooks, 1938-1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Photographs. Rotha personal stills., undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Biographical information, filmography, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Newspaper clippings, United States, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Scrapbook on films of the 1930's (Box 7, Folder 5)
- "Casts and units", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Newspaper clippings, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Newspaper clippings, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings re. his books, Abbey Theatre film, etc., undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook: clippings on German film, 1926-1928 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook: 'Films' clippings on film, 1920-1925 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Scrapbook: Clippings on film, Soviet cinema, 1925-1927 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Manchester England press clippings on film, 1940's (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook: Clippings of newspaper reviews, 1944-1954 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- "The Times." Script for film on the London Times, 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- "Cat and mouse." Scripts and plans., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- "A city speaks." Documentary, Manchester England, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Technical shooting script for air film, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- "Peace film" Controversy, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- "The phantom lobster.", 1950 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- "World of plenty.", 1942 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- "Cracle of genius" with correspondence for Abbey Theatre film, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- "World without end" inlucing press reviews, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- "The world is rich" with correspondence, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- "The face of Britain" and "Shipyard" scripts and scrapbook, 1930's (Box 12, Folder 3)
- "The face of Britain" script, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
- "The life of Adolf Hitler" scripts and corrrespondence, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- "The life of Adolf Hitler", 1961 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- "The life of Adolf Hitler", undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
- "The silent raid", 1962 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- "The silent raid", undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
- "The silent raid" and photographs, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- "Portrait of a flying Yorkshireman", undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
- "Portrait of a flying Yorkshireman" radio script, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- "Rotha on film", 1958 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- "Rotha on film." Proof copy of book, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
- "Documentary film", 1930's (Box 14, Folder 5)
- "Documentary film", 1952 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- "The little screen", 1952-1953 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- "The innocent eye", undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Flaherty a biography', circa 1959 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Tape recordings inludes four tapes from Rotha's films, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Tape recordings inludes five tapes from Rotha's films, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Periodicals with articles by or about Rotha, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Periodicals with articles by or about Rotha, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
- "Television in the making", 1956 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- "The film till now", 1930 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- The film till now", undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
- The film till now", 1949 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- "Celluloid", undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Lectures, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
- "Celluloid", undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Award diplomas, awards of merit, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Dust jackets designed by Rotha, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Documentary Diary (Secker & Warburg), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- I play upon a dream and article on Carl Dreyer's Gertrud, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
- London Transport Project, 1934-1935 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- The River of Life, includes photographs, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Kino Conference, Moscow, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- The Peace Film, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- The World is One, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Radio prorams, 1949-1954 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Nobel Prize Winners, 1955-1957 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Life of Adolf Hilter, and a brochure, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Film Encyclopedia, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- A Clockwork Orange, and materials re film by Stanley Kubric, 1968-1971 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Steel, memos re a projected film, circa 1930 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- The Living Newspaper, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- The Film Till Now, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- The Tongue-tied Canary, 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- D.W. Griffith, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Phantom Lobster, 1949-1950 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Portrait of a Flying Yorkshireman, 1950-1953 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- World Without End, 1952-1953 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Peggy and the American Soldier, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Flaherty biography Parts 1-2, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Flaherty biography Parts 3-4, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Flaherty biography Parts 5-6, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Glossary of TV Terms, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Fourth Estate, 1939-1940 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Fight to Survive, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Aborigines, correspondence, memos, and photographs, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- The Honeyspike, outline by Brian Macmahon, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- The Last Tango in Paris. Rotha was a court witness in an obsenity case against the United States, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Richard Winnington book, includes memorial Service for Winnington, 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Richard Winnington and correspondence, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Richard Winnington, 1953-1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Richard Winnington, 1972-1977 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Aftermath, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Alfred Salter Story, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Beauty Contest, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Ceasar's Dead Wife, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Come, Summer, Come, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Escape to England, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Fight for Life, based on G.F. Hughes' Bar Sinister, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
- The Fight of Youth (Two Women), undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Flame in the Air, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Forgiveness, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
- The Fox, by D.H. Lawrence, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Heaven and Earth, adpted from Vere Hutchinson's The Naked Man, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
- History of Medicine, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
- House in the Hollow, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
- The Laughing Cavalier or The Fairbanks Saga, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
- London River, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 16)
- The Long Day, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Meet the Baron, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 18)
- Memed, My Hawk, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
- Moment of Glory, undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
- The Oxford Film, undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
- The Pantomine, undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
- The Passionate People, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
- The Pathway, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 24)
- The Right to Vote, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 25)
- Romance of Immortals (Immortal Hero), undated (Box 22, Folder 26)
- Secrets in the Sun, based on Robert Harling's the Endless Colonnade, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 27)
- Selfridges (advertising film), undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
- Silent Raid (De Overval) produced in Holland by Rotha, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 29)
- Silicosi's Story, undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
- Storm over Snowdon, adapted from Elizabeth Coxhead's One Green Bottle, undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
- Story of Lloyds (Insurance film), undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
- A Taste for Honey, based on H.F. Heard's A Taste for Honey, circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 33)
- Teen-age Film, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 34)
- Television Report. Coleman, Prentis, & Variety, Ltd. and unrealized film projects, scripts, etc., 1953 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Thunder in the Air, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- To Die with Honor. Story of Hanna Senesch, based on Bar-Adon's Seven Who Fell, Syrkin's Blessed is the Match, and St. John's The Man Who Played God, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
- The Traitor. Based on Frank O'Conner's Jumbo's Wife, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Verdict of Twelve. Based on R.W. Postgate's novel., 1950 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Young Love in Cambridge, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Untitled-- English Countryside, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Corrrespondence. Film ideas: Josephine baker's children, Atomic Energy and electricity, The Baron (TV series), etc., 1951-1957 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Ministry of Food Meeting, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Drawings by Raul Rotha's brother J.R.F. Thompson, his grandmother's diary and color illustrations, 1905, 1916-1917 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- 8 Pens, and eight artcles by Rotha., 1928 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents
  The Downfall, Emile Zola. The Celebration of 8 Pens, The Madonna of Jermyn Street. As Seen Through a Glass Darkly. "Adieu! N'oubliez-pas la plus Miserable personne du monde." Food.
- Notebook cover for 8 Pens articles, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- 8 Pens, "Menu" commemorating the 50th meeting, illustrations by Rotha, 1928 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Reviews for the Conniseur, 1927-1929 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  A Young Artist's Exhibition. Mural Paintings at the Tate Gallery. The Paintings of Honoré Daumier, Some Studies in Ballet, The Fourth Centenary of Alrech Durer, Beauty and Fashion in the 'Sixties, Three "Avanced" Artists, Vincent Van Gogh, London Group Retrospective Exhibition, "Largilleére," by Georges Pascal, Toulouse-Latrec, An Artist and Two Painters, Illustrators of the Sixties, Aubrey Beardsley, Old Military Prints, The Pastel Society, Yesterday and To-day, Essays in Rotundity, "New English" Gloom, One Hundred Title-pages, 1500-1800, Amadeo Modigliani, 1885-1920, Unpublished article, La Grauvre Sur Bois Moderne de l'Occident, Orovida, Ridley Art Club, Henry Lamb, Nineteenth-Century Dutch Art, Lady Artists and More Lady Artists, Still More Lady Artists and Some Scottish Painters, A French Modernist, Abstraction, Rural England, Terminology, The Modern English Water-Colour Society, The Seven and Five Society, Eric Gill, The Goupil Salon, Interesting Tendencies, Fashionable, Elegancies, Mr. Edward Wadsworth, Society of Graphic Art, Mr. Walter Richard Sickert, British and French Sculpters, Still Photoraphy, New Interior Decoration, The New Spirit in Russian Theatre.
- Correspondence. Including his brother J.R.F. Thompson and others, includes a clipping and a photograph, 1932-1933 (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Diaries: Vol 1-5. Parts were excised before collection came to UCLA, 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 16)
- Diary: Vol 6, 1932-1933 (Box 23, Folder 17)
- Rotha's list of his art work, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
- Papilée., 1927 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Photographs. Scenes of Egypt and the Middle East, 1933 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Documentary Diary, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Documentary Diary Chapters 1-4, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Documentary Diary Chapters 5-11, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Peace Film. Scrapbook clippings re censorship of the film., 1936 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Art Work. Cover deisgns for novels. 2 books., 1927 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  Teuthhold, Peter. The Necromancer: or the tale of the Black Forest. Will, P. Horrid Mysteries, a story.
- Childhood work. Pencil drawings., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Aeolian Co. Proofs., 1926 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Th. Cantell Merchant Tailor Ads., 1927-1929 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Doughty, Frank Herbert. Book of Seamen., 1927-1929 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  Ink and watercolor illustrations and proofs.
- Dust jacket designs., circa 1930 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  The Mystery of Lore of Aparitions. The Flames of Moscow.
- Encyclopedia Britanica design by Paul de Rotha for 13th edition, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- History of Hats for Gentlemen., 1928 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  Art for unpublished book
- Mysteries of the Old Chateaux of France, 1928 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  Illustrations and proofs
- Thompson, C.J.S. Mystery & Lure of Perfume, 1926-1927 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Newspaper clippings, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  Ads for Encyclopedia Britanica and 1 book ad/.
- Wallis, Arthur. Tales of the Noresmen., 1927 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  London, Jonathan Cape
- Miscellaneous illustrations., 1923-1925 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous costume illustrations, circa 1920 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  Various media and 1 clipping of illustration by Bakst. 37 illustrations.
- Interview with Paul Rotha., 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  Transcript of video interview conducted by Trade Films for Paul Rotha's 75th birthday, 1982. Covers Rotha's career as a documentary film maker in the 1930's through 1940's. (Video cassette of interview housed in Instructional Media LIbrary, Room 46, Powell Library).
- Correspondence, Paul Rotha and Eric Knight., 1932-1943 (Box 26)
  To be sealed until July 1992. Contents in notebook: correspondence
- Photographs of Paul Rotha, undated (Box 27)
- Photographs; letters from Richard Griffith, 1931-1939 (Box 28)
- Letters from Richard Griffith, 1949-1969 (Box 29)
- Photographs; card index, undated (Box 30)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 31)
- Correspondence, 1960-1976 (Box 32)
- Correspondence, 1960-1976 (Box 33)
- Desk Diaries, undated (Box 34)
- Desk Diaries, undated (Box 35)
- Desk Diaries, undated (Box 36)
- Various printed materials, undated (Box 37)
- Various printed materials, undated (Box 38)
- Various printed materials; clippings, undated (Box 39)
- Books, undated (Box 40)
- Books, undated (Box 41)
- Books, undated (Box 42)
- Books, undated (Box 43)
- Books, undated (Box 44)
- Books, undated (Box 45)
- Books, undated (Box 46)
- Books, undated (Box 47)
- Books, undated (Box 48)
- Books, undated (Box 49)
- Books, undated (Box 50)
- Books, undated (Box 51)
- Books, undated (Box 52)
- Books, undated (Box 53)
- Various printed materials, undated (Box 54)
- Various printed materials; photographs, undated (Box 55)
- Magazines; scripts, undated (Box 56)
- Diaries; clippings; miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 57)
- Clippings; manuscripts; miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 58)
- Correspondence; scripts; misc papers, undated (Box 59)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 60)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 61)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 62)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 63)
- Diaries, some including drawings by Paul Rotha., 1920's (Box 64)
  Notesbooks; personal correspondence, 1920's memorabilia including 2 medallions, and cancelled passports. 2 scrolled items including movie posters and a family tree (Paul Thompson).
- Card index, undated (Box 65)
- Documentary drama, vol.2 - notes. (Box 66, Folder 1)
- Knight for vol.2., 1940/1943. (Box 66, Folder 2)
- Private letters, vol.2. (Box 66, Folder 3)
- Schrire, David. (Box 66, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Unfinished outline for film script.
- Pudovkin, Vsevolod. World of Plenty/Moi letters., 1942/1943. (Box 66, Folder 5)
- Documentary drama, vol.2. (Box 66, Folder 6)
  Photostats, press clippings.
- J.G. letters/articles, Crown Film Unit., 1944/1952. (Box 66, Folder 7)
- Newspaper clippings. (Box 66, Folder 8)
- Documentary drama index. (Box 66, Folder 9)
- Ireland, Cork, Jumbo, etc. (Box 66, Folder 10)
- Movie Parade. (Box 66, Folder 11)
- Knight, Eric. (Box 66, Folder 12)
  John Salt manuscript.
- Gee, Maggie. (Box 66, Folder 13)
- Research material for Golden Whip., 1963. (Box 67, Folder 1)
- National Film Theater PR films. (Box 67, Folder 2)
- Manuscript, articles, etc. (Box 67, Folder 3)
- Central Office of Information and Films of Fact crisis. (Box 67, Folder 4)
- Eric Knight letters. vol.2., 1939/1941. (Box 67, Folder 5)
- John Grierson letters (transcripts) to Basil Wright and Paul Rotha. vol.2., 1938/1942. (Box 67, Folder 6)
- Letters., 1938/1945. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  To and from: John Grierson, Hawes, Trevelyan, St. John.
- Letters, vol. II: Beddington, Balcoh, Rukeyser: Puck Fair, Rudgrave & Harling, BBC, British Lion. (Box 67, Folder 8)
- Dossiers. (Box 67, Folder 9)
- Griffith, Richard. Recent, up to, 1969. (Box 67, Folder 10)
- Letters, 1983. (Box 68, Folder 1)
- Letters, 1981. (Box 68, Folder 2)
- Letters, 1979. (Box 68, Folder 3)
- Letters, 1978. (Box 68, Folder 4)
- Elles, Reeve & Company., 1967 on. (Box 68, Folder 5)
- William Godfrey (old), CTBF, E.L. Clark, George Attenborough. (Box 68, Folder 6)
- Garbutt, Michael. (Box 68, Folder 7)
- Letters, 1980. (Box 69, Folder 1)
- Film Society. (Box 69, Folder 2)
- Oxford Film Workshop. (Box 69, Folder 3)
- Documentary diary letters re same: for correction in 2nd edition. (Box 69, Folder 4)
- Obituaries. (Box 69, Folder 5)
- Knight, Jere. (Box 69, Folder 6)
- Flaherty book letters. (Box 69, Folder 7)
- Eric Knight material, BBC broadcast, letters to Paul Rotha re Portrait of a Flying Yorkshireman. (Box 69, Folder 8)
- Letters, 1982. (Box 69, Folder 9)
- Ministry of Information Film Centre reports., 1940. (Box 69, Folder 10)
- British Film Institute and National Film Archive. (Box 70, Folder 1)
- John Grierson letters (chronological), vol.2. (Box 70, Folder 2)
- John Grierson: speeches & articles for vol.2., 1944/1945. (Box 70, Folder 3)
- PR notes on Documentary Diary, vol.2. (Box 70, Folder 4)
- Richard Griffith letters for vol.2., 1940/1948. (Box 70, Folder 5)
  (Extracted from a main file of Richard Griffith letters)
- World of Plenty letters - Ministry of Information. (Box 70, Folder 6)
- Schrire and Rotha. vol.2., 1939/1942. (Box 70, Folder 7)
- World Documentary, British Documentary, WWE papers. (Box 70, Folder 8)
- Boyle and Ormerod: Gerald Aggett vs. Paul Rotha. (Box 70, Folder 9)
- Association of Cinematograph and Allied Technicians. (Box 70, Folder 10)
- Norway, Sweden, Trento (Italy). (Box 71, Folder 1)
- Trevelyan, John. (Box 71, Folder 2)
- Australia - Holmes, etc. (Box 71, Folder 3)
- Press cuttings of general topics. (Box 71, Folder 4)
  (Brecht, Dilys Powell's U.S. articles, jazz, Eire, electricity, color-bar, teddy boys, Cripp's biography, etc)
- General., 1961. (Box 71, Folder 5)
- Clippings - Film 1. (Box 71, Folder 6)
- Royal Literary Fund, Society of Authors. (Box 72, Folder 1)
- Paul Rotha Productions. (Box 72, Folder 2-3)
  Old file.
- Memos, letters, etc., 1945/1946. (Box 72, Folder 4)
- Sundry memoranda, vol.2. (Box 72, Folder 5)
- World is Rich letters. (Box 73, Folder 1)
- Films of Fact Company letters. (Box 73, Folder 2-4)
- Ann Griffith, Jere Knight. (Box 73, Folder 5)
- Freeling, Nicholas. (Box 73, Folder 6)
- BBC TV. (Box 73, Folder 7)
- The Listener., May 1, 1969 and May 15, 1969. (Box 74, Folder 1)
- Sunday Times Magazine., March 15, 1970. (Box 74, Folder 2)
- Press cuttings. (Box 74, Folder 3)
- Summary of The Honeyspike, by Bryan McMahon., 1967. (Box 74, Folder 4)
- Monotypes. (Box 74, Folder 5)
- The Raid, by Dr. de Jong. (Box 74, Folder 6)
- Isotype Institute (Otto Neurath letters to Paul Rotha and others)., November 1941-December 1947. (Box 74, Folder 7)
- British Film Academy., 1935/1953. (Box 74, Folder 8)
- The Observer., September 3, 1967. (Box 75, Folder 1)
- Documentary Diary typescript copy sent to J.G., December 1970. (Box 75, Folder 2)
- Letters to Miss C.F. Thompson from Holland, Hamburg and Hollywood. (Box 75, Folder 3)
- British Film Academy, file 2. (Box 75, Folder 4)
- Richard Winnington Award. (Box 75, Folder 5)
- Documentary Diary One letters, etc. (Box 75, Folder 6)
- Richard Winnington press reviews. (Box 76, Folder 1)
- Films of Fact letters. (Box 76, Folder 2)
- CIST History of Medicine. (Box 76, Folder 3)
- Documentary is Neither Long Nor Short. (Box 76, Folder 4)
- Manchester Civics Film script. (Box 76, Folder 5)
- A City Speaks synopsis. (Box 76, Folder 6)
- Press cuttings, general. (Box 76, Folder 7)
- Weekend Review cuttings. (Box 76, Folder 8)
- Phantom Lobster memorandum. (Box 76, Folder 9)
- Godfrey Insurance (new) etc. (Box 76, Folder 10)
- Future's in the Air. (Box 76, Folder 11)
- Film crisis press cuttings., 1949. (Box 76, Folder 12)
- National Film Theater compilation film programme., 1963. (Box 77, Folder 1)
- Germany (Buckland Smith)., 1948/1949. (Box 77, Folder 2)
- Letters., 1966. (Box 77, Folder 3)
- Cat and Mouse. (Box 77, Folder 4)
- U.S. visit., 1957. (Box 77, Folder 5)
- Film industry cuttings. (Box 77, Folder 6)
- London Blitz cuttings. (Box 77, Folder 7)
- Could Be! by Norman Corwin. (Box 77, Folder 8)
- A - R., 1955/1957. (Box 77, Folder 9)
- World Without End., 1952/1953. (Box 77, Folder 10)
  Letters, Warner's narration.
- Phantom Lobster letters. (Box 78, Folder 1)
- Puck Fair by Muriel Rukeyser. (Box 78, Folder 2)
- Australia, vol.2. (Box 78, Folder 3)
- vol.3, book 3., 63 copies. (Box 78, Folder 4)
- Hitler film., 40 copies. (Box 78, Folder 5)
- Australia., 6 copies. (Box 78, Folder 6)
- Vol.2, book 2., 71 copies. (Box 78, Folder 7)
- Documentary Diary 1, vol.2. (Box 78, Folder 8)
  Clipings, letters, etc.